SUBHANSHU MOHAN GUPTA

- ♥ SubhanshuMG in https://www.linkedin.com/in/subhanshu-mohan-gupta-039559123/ SubhanshuMG

SUMMARY

I'm a DevOps/Cloud, Front-End Engineer, and a 3rd-year junior currently pursuing B.Tech (CSE) having experience in developing various software solutions with efficient coding techniques and practices. Apart from the core development, I love to spend my free time playing games and exploring new things, etc. My only desire is to do just what is necessary for making this world a better place to live.

EDUCATION

Amity University Lucknow

July 2019 - July 2023

Bachelor's of Technology Computer Science and Engineering 2023 XII-89.4%, X-9.2 CGPA

EMPLOYMENT

CGCS, Junior Software Engineer, Hyderabad, Remote

Oct. 2021 - Current

Responsible for deployment of pipelines and application environments which includes the continuous implementation of DevOps principles and tooling for system, performance, scalability, reliability, security, and fault tolerance

- Setting up and maintaining CI/CD web application server environments and pipelines with tools and technologies like Docker, Jenkins, and Kubernetes.
- Actively managing AWS accounts and making recommendations on how best to support the infrastructure.
- Provisioning and maintaining development and production servers.
- Supporting development teams with project builds, deployments, and troubleshooting.

Google Developer Students Club - Amity University Lucknow, Cloud Lead, Lucknow

Sept. 2021 - Current

Managing and organizing events related to the cloud.

- Recently collaborated with Cantilever Labs.

LoveONN, SDE Intern, South Australia, Remote

Nov. 2020 - Feb. 2021

Worked on a CRM software using Node.js, CSS, HTML, JAVA & Git.

Also, on development of code snippets to add functionality to few softwares under the organization which included the usage of the languages like JavaScript and Python.

EDAInfront Solutions, Web Developer, Remote

Mar. 2020 - May 2020

Operated as a Web Developer and made several static sites from templates and websites using WordPress & integrated services on web.

SKILLS

WEB DEVELOPMENT: HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, Node.is, MySQL, BootStrap DEVOPS/CLOUD: AWS - EC2, S3, SNS, RDS, EBS, IAM, Lambda, CLI, Cloudwatch, Jenkins, Git/GitHub/GitLab, Docker, GCP, Ansible PROGRAMMING LANGUAGES: C, C++, JAVA, Python

PROJECTS

WebRES | NTCC May 2020 - June 2020

WebRES is an HTML5 app that lets you test websites at a variety of resolutions very quickly. It also works on mobile, which allows you to test websites at a variety of widths on a phone or tablet where you can't normally change the width of the browser.

Sorting Visualizer | NTCC Sept. 2021 - Oct. 2021

A visualization of 5 sorting algorithms including Quick Sort, Merge Sort, Selection Sort, Bubble Sort and Insertion Sort.

Feb. 2020 - Mar. 2020 Geolocation

Geologation helps you to track your current location with numerous features provided.

CERTIFICATIONS

AWS Certified Solutions Architect - Associate, Amazon Web Services (AWS)

Issued Oct 2021 · Expires Oct 2023

VOLUNTEERING

Source Code Society, Core Member Aug. 2019 - Current

Lucknow

Working on frontend development and various projects and finding the most efficient algorithms for executing particular tasks.

July 2019 - Current

Amity Education Group, Event Co-ordinator

Responsible for managing events at Eco/Unnati club of Amity University Lucknow.